### **CURRICULUM VITÆ**

# **Sunyin Elisbrown Sigala**

#### Software Engineer, IT Technician.

+237679690703 | sunyinelisbrown@gmail.com | Bonas, Yaounde, Cameroon.

#### **Professional Summary**

I am a Testout PC Pro Certified IT Technician with a genuine passion for Computer software engineering. My coding skills are commendable, and I have a high-level aptitude for various coding languages. Additionally, I am an expert-level IT technician with exceptional critical thinking and problem-solving abilities.

#### **Skills**

- Software installation and maintenance,
- Network security and administration,
- Computer hardware installation and Maintenance,
- Troubleshooting and debugging,
- Microsoft Excel, Word and PowerPoint,

- Technical problem-solving,
- Performance Improvement,
- Coding in C, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, PHP, Bootstrap, and (React.js, Node.js) in progress.
- Security system Administration.

#### **Experience**

### Software Engineering Intern GlobexCam Group, GP Melen, Yaounde.

June 2022 - August 2022

- Contributed to advancements in company internship experiences by offering thorough and knowledgeable feedback.
- Shared growth and knowledge development with detailed technical presentations.
- Helped develop and improve Food-ordering and ticket reservation programs under the supervision of a qualified software engineering team.
- Further developed abilities and cemented acquired knowledge with a learning-focused mindset.
- Chose and developed a capstone project alongside sponsoring professionals.
- Installed and configured a network printer within the office setting.

# Night Security Guard EXHIST University, Yaounde.

August 2022 - December 2022

• Contributed to total building security, effectively distributing resources to cover all access points and building areas.

- Viewed monitor screens and remained alert to movement on-screen for authorized and unauthorized individuals.
- Secured building against intrusion, routinely checking and locking windows and doors.
- Identified security concerns with regular facility and equipment inspections.
- Investigated disturbances, alarms and unusual activities.
- Permitted authorized persons to enter the property upon identity verification.

## Content and Social Media Manager "Nature We Like", Fouda, Yaounde.

February 2023 - March 2023

- I created a complete social media and online presence for the phytotherapeutics company.
- Tracked customer engagement and feedback to optimize social media strategies.
- Oversaw social media asset design to be in line with brand identity.
- Incorporated interesting and informative content, resulting in increased shares and followers.
- Created benchmarks for measuring the impact of social media programs to analyze and report on the effectiveness of campaigns.

# Advanced Level Computer Science and ICT teacher Divine Success Center, Simbock, Yaounde.

**January 2023 - June 2023** 

- Promoted students' technological development, regularly assessing progress with material and adapting strategies.
- Delivered instruction on critical and computational thinking, digital citizenship and technology literacy.
- Planned and implemented instructional programs in line with system-wide goals and priorities to meet student needs.
- Controlled student behaviour and delivered organized lectures to maintain a learning-focused and structured environment.
- Taught students the basics of computer science, hardware configuration and entry-level coding.
- Updated administration on students' abilities and incorporated feedback to continuously improve program offerings.
- Supported students' intellectual, physical, social and emotional development with a supportive and learning-focused instructional environment.

#### Education

# Higher National Diploma (HND) in Software Engineering EXHIST University.

October 2021 - August 2023

- I was elected as the public relations officer for the Student Union at EXHIST (SUEX 2021).
- Was Awarded a full scholarship to study Cloud computing and take CompTIA A+ certifications exams.
- Scholar at OPEN Dreams Foundation.
- Continuing education in Cloud computing and Network security.

#### **Testout PC Pro Certification**

December 2023

#### https://certification.testout.com/verifycert/6-2C6-VAUVFN

- Master hardware/software repairs for peak performance.
- Build & manage PC systems from scratch.
- Tame tangled networks, wired & wireless.
- Conquer OS & driver issues with expert skills.
- Become a tech hero for in-person & remote support.
- Keep systems healthy with updates, scans, & backups.
- Connect & troubleshoot printers, scanners, & more.
- Guard data privacy with robust security measures.
- Document procedures clearly for future reference.
- Adapt to change by staying current with tech trends.

### CompTIA A+ Certification NoelTech Solutions, 609 SE Huron Blvd USA

In Progress

- Perform hardware and software troubleshooting to identify and resolve technical issues.
- Install, configure, and maintain computer systems, including desktops, laptops, and peripherals.
- Set up and troubleshoot network connections, both wired and wireless.
- Diagnose and repair hardware and software problems related to operating systems, applications, and drivers.
- Provide technical support to end-users, both in-person and remotely.
- Perform routine maintenance tasks like system updates, virus scans, and data backups.
- Assist in the setup and configuration of printers, scanners, and other peripheral devices.
- Ensure data security and privacy by implementing appropriate security measures.
- Document technical procedures, solutions, and troubleshooting steps.
- Stay updated with the latest technology trends and advancements in the IT industry.

### AWS Cloud Practitioner NoelTech Solutions, 609 SE Huron Blvd USA

In Progress

- Design, deploy, and manage cloud-based applications and infrastructure.
- Configure and administer AWS services such as EC2, S3, RDS, and VPC.
- Implement cloud-based security and compliance measures.
- Optimize cloud-based performance and costs.
- Troubleshoot and resolve cloud-based issues.
- Stay up-to-date on the latest AWS services and features.

### Language

English (Proficient)

French (Advanced)

### **Hobbies**

I love doing pencil art, listening to music and working out.